<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>UIUC ASB</title><description>An Astro Theme for Visual Storytelling</description><link>https://verse-astro.vercel.app/</link><language>en-US</language><item><title>Alternative Seasonal Breaks at UIUC</title><link>https://verse-astro.vercel.app/posts/about-asb/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://verse-astro.vercel.app/posts/about-asb/</guid><description>&lt;br&gt; 🌲 Student-run program of the University YMCA &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; 🚐 Volunteer across the US during spring break &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; 🛠️ Make a meaningful impact on social issues &lt;br&gt;</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>**Alternative Seasonal Breaks** is a 100% student run, non-profit volunteer organization of the University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign and the University YMCA.

Each trip offers participant a unique, hands-on opportunity to make a difference in the lives of both communities and individuals nation-wide.

ASB&apos;s mission is to educate students about social, political, and environmental issues through direct service, group reflections, student leadership, diversity, and engagement beyond the local community. Participants will develop empathy and be motivated to action with the local community.</content:encoded></item><item><title>History</title><link>https://verse-astro.vercel.app/posts/our-history/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://verse-astro.vercel.app/posts/our-history/</guid><description>Alternative Seasonal Breaks is a 100% student run, non-profit volunteer organization of the University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign and the University YMCA.</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>Alternative Seasonal Breaks was founded in 1989 by a group of University of Illinois students wanting to work with Central American refugees in Brownsville, Texas. Maria Somma, then program director of the University YMCA, organized the trip along with 22 volunteers. They lived and worked for a week in the Rio Grande Valley with the refugees.

In 1990, ASB expanded the program with three trips: a return trip to the Rio Grande Valley, a trip to Harlem dealing with homelessness, and a trip to South Dakota working with Native American issues. Since then, ASB has grown to offer a variety of trips.

After COVID, the group was re-formed by YMCA Student Board President and current ASB co-president Lily Rybka in 2023.

ASB is still a program of the University YMCA and continues working to provide university students the opportunity to directly work with and learn about a variety of social justice issues.</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>